{"tossups": [{"question": "This event gave rise to the \"golden youth,\" club-wielding street gangs known for their musk perfume. Supporters of this event commemorated the period before it with \"victim's balls.\" This event was followed by the White Terror, and it resulted in the repeal of the Law of the Maximum and the Law of Suspects. A target of this event was mysteriously shot in the jaw after being arrested in the Hotel de Ville. This event ended the power of the Committee of Public Safety. For the point, name this period of the French Revolution in which the Reign of Terror was ended.", "answer": "<b><u>Thermidor</u></b>ian Reaction (prompt on \u201cFrench Revolution\u201d until mention)  {II}", "metadata": "JB"}, {"question": "This group's leader was sued by Elmer Gertz, the lawyer of a man shot by a Chicago police officer. The second leader of this group died when Korean Airlines flight 007 was shot down by the Soviets and was Congressman Larry McDonald. This group's founder got rich making Sugar Daddies, a type of caramel lollipop. Founded by Robert Welch, this group was named for a Baptist missionary killed in China and sometimes said to be the \"first American casualty of the Cold War.\" The founder of Koch Industries was one of its first members. For the point, name this right-wing, anti-Communist group founded in 1958.", "answer": "<b><u>John Birch</u></b> Society [or <b><u>JBS</u></b>; accept <b><u>Robert Welch Inc.</u></b> until mentioned]  {III}", "metadata": "MC"}, {"question": "One co-written book which defines this time period as the culmination of \"identity logic\" contains excursuses on Odysseus and the Marquis de Sade's Justine. Michel Foucault's 1984 essay asking about this period quotes heavily from an earlier essay that put forth \"Argue as much as you will\u2026but obey!\" and \"Dare to know\" as maxims emblematic of it. Theodor Adorno and Max Horkheimer of the Frankfurt School wrote that the <em>Dialectic of</em> this time period led to the Holocaust within about 150 years. For the point, name this period of intellectual history defined as \"man's emergence from his self-imposed immaturity\" by Immanuel Kant, who was a member.", "answer": "the <b><u>Enlightenment</u></b> [or <b><u>Aufkl\u00e4rung</u></b>; or <em>Dialectic of</em> <em><b><u>Enlightenment</u></b></em>; or \"What Is <b><u>Enlightenment</u></b>?\"]  {III}", "metadata": "MJ"}, {"question": "A separate electorate for this group was proposed in the Communal Award, which was replaced by the Poona Pact. The Prevention of Atrocities Act sought to protect this group, which is officially part of the Scheduled Tribes. Members of this group were encouraged to take the 22 Vows during mass conversions held by B. R. Ambedkar. This group is sometimes called the \"children of God,\" or harijan, and was traditionally viewed as outside the four varnas. For the point, name this historically-shunned group in the Indian caste system.", "answer": "<b><u>dalit</u></b>s [or <b><u>untouchable</u></b>s; or <b><u>harijan</u></b> before read; or <b><u>scheduled</u></b> castes before read]  {III}", "metadata": "JB"}, {"question": "This man moved the relics of Saint Columba from Iona to Dunkeld to protect them from Vikings. This man was succeeded by his brother Donald I, and his sons Constantine I and Aed also held the throne. This man\u2019s connection to the Gaelic kingdom of Dal Riata is unclear, and it is believed that he inherited the throne from his Pictish mother rather than conquering Pictland. Under the reign of Donald II, this man became known as the first King of Alba. For the point, which man nicknamed The Conqueror is considered the first king of Scotland?", "answer": "<b><u>Kenneth MacAlpin</u></b> [or <b><u>Kenneth I</u></b> of Scotland; prompt on <b><u>Kenneth</u></b>]  {III}", "metadata": "TR"}, {"question": "This substance\u2019s production had similar implications as Hermann Kolbe\u2019s later synthesis of acetic acid, since it too advanced structural theory. This substance was found while trying to synthesize ammonium cyanate, which ended up decomposing to become this product. The synthesis of this compound by Friedrich Wohler is considered the start of modern organic chemistry. Vitalism was disproved by synthesizing this organic compound without even using a kidney. For the point, name this compound with formula CO(NH2)2 that is found in the urine.", "answer": "<b><u>urea</u></b>  {III}", "metadata": "Ike"}, {"question": "A powerful man to hold this post was nicknamed \"The Abominable No Man.\" A man resigned from this post after reports he had accepted an expensive overcoat and rug from a Boston textile manufacturer. In the Carter administration, this post was held by a man who reportedly participated in cocaine fueled parties at Studio 54. Those men were Sherman Adams and Hamilton Jordan. In the Nixon administration, it was held by Alexander Haig & H.R. Haldeman.  For the point, name this position, the highest ranking employee of the White House Office.", "answer": "White House <b><u>Chief of Staff</u></b>  {III}", "metadata": "MC"}, {"question": "This person issued the Edict of Saint-Germain and the Edict of Amboise. This woman and her family were nearly kidnapped during the Surprise at Meaux (pr. MOE). This woman's husband was killed by a lance to the eye while celebrating the Peace of Cateau-Cambresis. She is sometimes blamed for the assassination of Admiral Gaspard de Coligny, which occurred after Marguerite of Valois married the future Henry IV. For the point, name this Queen of France who supported the St Bartholomew's Day Massacre and was from a Florentine family.", "answer": "<b><u>Catherine</u></b> de' <b><u>Medici</u></b> [or <b><u>Caterina</u></b> de <b><u>Medici</u></b>; prompt on partial answers]", "metadata": "JB"}, {"question": "In a song added to this musical's 2004 revival, citizens sing that \"something just broke\" as they heard sad news. Unhinged rants from a man in a Santa Claus suit, Samuel Byck, interrupt this musical. In its first song, a derelict amusement park's Proprietor declares \"Everybody's got a right to their dreams.\" After a scene showing the hanging of Charles Guiteau, its cast gathers in a Dallas apartment to try and encourage a doubtful Lee Harvey Oswald to pull the trigger. For 10 points, name this 1990 Stephen Sondheim musical about historical people who tried to kill a U.S. President.", "answer": "<em><b><u>Assassins</u></b></em>  {III}", "metadata": "MJ"}, {"question": "A king of these people was killed after inviting his wife Rosamund to drink from the skull of her father. These people had officials called gastalds, which were granted authority by the Edict of Rothari. A history of these people was penned by Paul the Deacon. Kings of these people include Alboin, Liutprand, and a man who was defeated by Charlemagne, Desiderius. The Iron Crown was a symbol of these people, who founded duchies at Spoleto and Benevento. For the point, name this Germanic people that name an Italian region with a capital at Milan.", "answer": "<b><u>Lombard</u></b>s [or <b><u>Langobard</u></b>s]  {III}", "metadata": "JB"}, {"question": "Two acts proposed by this man were influenced by his mentor, the economist Henry Carey. A law sponsored by this man was enforced by Poland Act and sought to ban the Mormon practice of bigamy.The Hatch Act extended a law proposed by this politician, who also names a high tariff passed in 1861. This man names a bill which sought to establish institutions for agricultural education. For the point, name this Vermont senator who sponsored an 1862 law which allowed the creation of land-grant colleges.", "answer": "Justin Smith <b><u>Morrill</u></b>  {III}", "metadata": "JB"}, {"question": "In order to avoid participating in one of these events, the noblewoman Sophonisba poisoned herself. One of these events was disrupted when three elephants got stuck under an archway. Participants in these events probably did not actually paint their faces red. The Ovation was a lesser version of this sort of event. A laurel wreath crown was used during these events, which centered on a chariot ride down the Via Sacra. For the point, name this sort of event in which Roman generals were celebrated for their victories.", "answer": "<b><u>triumph</u></b>s  {III}", "metadata": "JB"}, {"question": "A religious leader from this country led the Doleantie schism and founded the Anti- Revolutionary Party.This is the northernmost country where religious groups were split by pillarization, a policy promoted here by Abraham Kuyper (<b>pr. KYE-per</b>). In this modern-day country, the Five Articles of Remonstrance were signed by followers of a man whose teachings were condemned at the Council of Dort, Jacobus Arminius. The Mennonite Church was founded in this country, where the Pilgrims briefly lived in the city of Leiden. For the point, name this country where Calvinism was practiced by the House of Orange.", "answer": "<b><u>Netherlands</u></b> [or <b><u>Nederland</u></b>; or <b><u>Holland</u></b>]  {III}", "metadata": "JB"}, {"question": "This team retired #3 in honor of a man who never played for them and was their most frequent opponent. Abe Saperstein gave this team a more \"exotic\" home even though the original players were all from Illinois. Its most famous player in the 1970's was Fred \"Curly\" Neal. This team is owned by one of the most powerful African-American executives, Mannie Jackson. In a loss, it once gave up a buzzer beater to 50-year old Red Klotz, who said \"you'd have thought we'd killed Santa.\" This team's theme song is a whistled version of \"Sweet Georgia Brown.\" For the point, name this exhibition basketball team who specialized in comedy stunts.", "answer": "Harlem <b><u>Globetrotters</u></b> [or <b><u>Harlem</u></b>; or Chicago <b><u>Globetrotters</u></b>; or New York Harlem <b><u>Globetrotters</u></b>]  {III}", "metadata": "MC"}, {"question": "A pamphlet advocating the broadening of this party\u2019s electoral base was \u201cWe must get out of the tower!\u201d A candidate from this party came second in the 1925 election after Ernst Thalmann of the KPD split the vote. Besides Wilhelm Marx, this party\u2019s other leaders include Heinrich Bruning, the longest continuously serving Weimar chancellor, and Franz von Papen. This political party was formed to resist Bismarck\u2019s Kulturkampf. For the point, name this German political party that represented the interests of the largest non-Protestant denomination.", "answer": "Catholic <b><u>Centre</u></b> Party [or German <b><u>Centre</u></b> Party; or the Deutsche <b><u>Zentrum</u></b>spartei]  {III}", "metadata": "PL"}, {"question": "An award-winning 2008 history of this indigenous group by Finnish-born historian Pekka H\u00e4m\u00e4l\u00e4inen called its territory an Empire. A chieftain of this native people named Quanah Parker surrendered in 1874 along with the Kiowa and Cheyenne, ending the Red River War. This group broke off from the Shoshone in the mid-18th century, after which their dozens of \"bands\" acquired the horses they used in deadly raids on Mexico and the Republic of Texas. For the point, name this dominant Indian group of the early 19th-century southern Great Plains.", "answer": "<b><u>Comanche</u></b> tribe [or <b><u>Comanche</u></b>r\u00eda]  {III}", "metadata": "MJ"}, {"question": "The target of this event had the slogan \u201cevolution in continuity\u201d and proclaimed a \u201cpolitical spring.\u201d Following this event, Mario Soares was the first person to be freely elected Prime Minister, since this event was followed by a two year Continuing Revolutionary Process led by the National Salvation Junta. The target of this event hid in the Largo do Carmo police station before surrendering to General Spinola. The MFA led this event, which is commemorated by Freedom Day on April 25th, the day on which it occurred. For the point, name this event which ousted Marcello Caetano in Portugal, named for a certain flower.", "answer": "<b><u>Carnation Revolution</u></b>  {III}", "metadata": "JZ"}, {"question": "It's not Clinton, but it was the surname of the first Chairman of the Erie Canal Commission. A man with this surname used a pegleg after getting his leg caught in his carriage wheels and died using a whale bone to clear his urinary tract. Another man with this surname influenced Alexander Hamilton with a document called \"On Public Credit\" drafted during his time as Superintendent of Finance. This was the surname of the so-called \"Financier of the Revolution\" from Pennsylvania and a New Yorker who wrote the Constitution's preamble. For the point, name the surname of Founding Fathers Robert and Gouverneur.", "answer": "<b><u>Morris</u></b>  {III}", "metadata": "MC"}, {"question": "A minimalist \u201cnew\u201d style at this theater was introduced when it re-opened in 1951. The pit in this theater is designed to keep the orchestra invisible, and the tradition of dimming the house lights for performances started here. This theater\u2019s namesake circle espoused \u201cvolkisch\u201d politics put forth by its founder\u2019s wife Cosima. For twenty years it was the only venue allowed to perform a music drama about the namesake Arthurian knight\u2019s search for the Grail, <em>Parsifal</em>. For the point, what opera house in a namesake German town was established by Richard Wagner for performances of his own works?", "answer": "<b><u>Bayreuth</u></b> Festspielhaus  {III}", "metadata": "CW"}, {"question": "The pottery of this culture frequently depicts strings of trophy-heads along a mythical killer whale. This culture created underground irrigation channels called puquios. Thomas Woodman dubiously claimed that this culture used cotton hot-air balloons. This people had a capital at Cahuachi and were influenced by the preceding Paracas culture. This culture created images of hummingbirds and monkeys by removing red pebbles from the desert ground. For the point, name this South American civilization known for their geoglyph \"lines.\"", "answer": "<b><u>Nazca</u></b> culture (do not accept or prompt on \u201cInca\u201d)  {II}", "metadata": "JB"}, {"question": "A famous photo taken in this city shows the stunned reaction of the tan suited Jim Leavelle. In this city, a man was arrested with a forced draft card made out to Alek James Hidell. During interrogations in this city, a man insisted he was only arrested because he had previously \"lived in the Soviet Union.\" A man was arrested at a screening of the film <em>War is Hell</em> here shortly after killing police officer J.D. Tippit. That shooter was then soon after shot himself in the basement of this city's police headquarters by a nightclub owner. For the point, name this city where Jack Ruby shot presidential assassin Lee Harvey Oswald.", "answer": "<b><u>Dallas</u></b>, Texas  {III}", "metadata": "MC"}, {"question": "One character played by this actor leads the title group in the theft of 14,000 gold bars during World War II in a 1970 film called Kelly\u2019s Heroes. Two of this director's films share a scene in which a flamethrower is used to clear out a bunker on the beach. One of those two 2006 films by this director was about a soldier who befriends a soldier kicked out of the Kempeitai and buries Tadamichi Kuribayashi, while the other is about the men who raised a flag on Mt. Suribachi. For the point, name this American director of <em>Flags of Our Fathers</em> and<em> Letters from Iwo Jima.</em>", "answer": "Clinton \u201cClint\u201d <b><u>Eastwood</u></b> Jr.  {III}", "metadata": "PL"}, {"question": "In 1994, this man raised a then-record 16 million dollars from direct mail solicitations when running for the Senate. This Republican lost to Charles Robb during a failed 1994 bid for the Senate in Virginia. In 1990, the ACLU helped this man get his convictions vacated from a scandal that involved his secretary, Fawn Hall, shredding numerous documents. While serving as a National Security Council staffer, he masterminded arms deals that channeled profits to the enemies of the Sandinistas. For the point, name this Marine Corps lieutenant colonel who was convicted for his role in the Iran-Contra scandal.", "answer": "Oliver \u201cOllie\u201d <b><u>North</u></b>  {III}", "metadata": "MC"}, {"question": "According to one account, before this battle, Amompharetus initially refused to retreat with the army and his division was left behind. The losing commander here was killed by a stone hurled by Aeimnestus, and his forces\u2019 sparabara formation proved too light. Aristodemus charged alone into the enemy lines in this battle to redeem his perceived cowardice. This battle supposedly took place on the same day as the naval Battle of Mycale. In this battle, Aristides the Just served under Pausanias, whose forces killed Mardonius. For the point, name this battle which took place after the battle of Salamis, the final land battle of the Greco-Persian Wars.", "answer": "Battle of <b><u>Plataea</u></b>  {III}", "metadata": "JZ"}, {"question": "This system was documented in Robert Hughes's book The Fatal Shore. The Bigge report criticized Lachlan Macquarie's implementation of this system, which involved lenient treatment of \"exclusives\" and \"emancipists.\" Participants in this system often stayed in moored boats called \"hulks\" before entering it. This system began with the arrival of the \"First Fleet\", which established a colony in Botany Bay at Sydney. For the point, identify this system by which criminals were shipped off to colonies on a certain island continent.", "answer": "transportation of <b><u>convicts</u></b> to <b><u>Australia</u></b> [or <b><u>penal</u></b> colonies in <b><u>Australia</u></b>; or obvious equivalents indicating <b><u>criminal</u></b>s being sent to <b><u>Australia</u></b>; prompt on partial answers]  {III}", "metadata": "JB"}, {"question": "Jay Robert Nash claims this man survived by using double \"Jimmy Lawrence\" to take his place the night he supposedly died. This man was frequently aided by girlfriend Billie Frechette. While staying at the Little Bohemia Lodge, he was chased after by Melvin Purvis. This leader of the Terror Gang had such confederates as George \"Baby Face\" Nelson. This man was set up in a sting involving Anna Sage, the \"woman in red,\" who went with him to see <em>Manhattan</em> <em>Melodrama</em> at the Biograph.For the point, name this Depression-era gangster who was killed coming out of a Chicago movie theater in 1934.", "answer": "John <b><u>Dillinger</u></b>  {III}", "metadata": "MC"}, {"question": "This statement was shown to be independent of several others by Beltrami, who used a map from the pseudosphere to the unit disk. George Bolyai created a \u201cstrange, new universe\u201d by assuming that this statement was not true. Playfair and Walls\u2019 axioms are equivalent to it. A corollary of this law states that the interior angles of a triangle will always sum to 180 degrees. It was introduced in its formulator\u2019s book <em>Elements</em>. This statement requires that a line and a point exist on a plane. For the point, name this member of Euclid\u2019s postulates that states certain types of lines will never intersect.", "answer": "<b><u>parallel</u></b> postulate [or Euclid\u2019s <b><u>fifth</u></b> postulate]  {III}", "metadata": "Ike"}, {"question": "This man decided to keep his country neutral after a meeting at Hendaye. He saved the enclave of Melilla after leading a forced march of the Legi\u00f3n Extranjera; that campaign took place during the war against the Abd el-Krim brothers. This man took power with the help of fellow <em>africanistas.</em> Despite his neutrality, he sent the \u201cBlue Division\u201d to fight in World War II. He declared that after his death, Juan Carlos would succeed him. After taking power, this man merged the Carlists with his own Falange party. For the point, name this right-wing dictator of Spain.", "answer": "Francisco <b><u>Franco</u></b> Bahamonde [prompt on <b><u>El Caudillo</u></b>]  {III}", "metadata": "SH"}, {"question": "This politician aided the cause of Andrew Furuseth by sponsoring the Seaman's Act to protect sailors' rights. This husband of the suffragist Belle Case set himself aside in favor of Montana Democrat Thomas Walsh when it came time to pick a leader of the Congressional Teapot Dome investigation. This one-time running mate of Burton Wheeler was succeeded in the Senate by a son of the same name, who was in turn succeeded by Joe McCarthy. For the point, name this advocate of the pro-labor union \"Wisconsin idea,\" a 1924 third-party presidential candidate and leading Progressive nicknamed \"Fightin' Bob\".", "answer": "Robert \"Fightin' Bob\" <b><u>LaFollette</u></b>, Sr.", "metadata": "MJ"}, {"question": "This man's greatest victory was defeating Samuel Sturgis at the Battle of Brice's Crossroads. After the Battle of Chickamauga, this man was reassigned for making death threats against superior Braxton Bragg. This officer first distinguished himself by leading 4,000 troops in an escape from Fort Donelson. He apocryphally claimed his secret was getting \"there firstest with the mostest.\" This general was accused of leading a massacre of black soldiers at Fort Pillow. For the point, name this Confederate cavalry leader who was also the first Grand Wizard of the Ku Klux Klan.", "answer": "Nathan Bedford <b><u>Forrest</u></b>  {III}", "metadata": "MC"}, {"question": "During this event, Emperor Suzong\u2019s generals, Guo Ziyi and Li Guangbi, appropriated soldiers from the Uighur Khanate. The namesake of this event was assassinated by his son, who was later assassinated by General Shi Siming, a childhood friend of the namesake of this event. Angry soldiers killed Minister Yang Guozhong during this event and caused Imperial Consort Yang Guifei, one of the Four Beauties, to be strangled. The namesake of this event created the Yan dynasty. For the point, name this rebellion during the reign of Emperor Xuanzong of the Tang, led by a namesake Sogdian general.", "answer": "<b><u>An Lushan</u></b> rebellion [or <b><u>An-shi</u></b> rebellion; <b><u>Tianbao</u></b> rebellion]  {III}", "metadata": "JZ"}, {"question": "At the end of this leader's rule, he gave a final speech in the Yugoslav embassy before being captured and deported. This leader's first term in office was supported by G.M. Malenkov. This leader lifted the ban on political parties, allowing the Smallholder's Party and National Peasants' Party to re-exist. This leader removed his country from the Warsaw Pact, an act that triggered the USSR to invade the country and force him out, replacing him with Janos (pr. <b>YAH-noash</b>) Kadar. For the point, name this Hungarian Chairman who was executed following a failed 1956 revolution.", "answer": "Imre <b><u>Nagy</u> </b> {III}", "metadata": "JL"}, {"question": "Amos Doolittle made four engravings depicting this campaign. During the final stages of this campaign, 78-year-old Samuel Whittemore, acting alone, killed three enemy soldiers and miraculously survived being bayoneted multiple times. During this campaign, Jason Russell's house in Menotomy was the target of an ambush. This campaign began with a standoff between John Pitcairn and John Parker. Samuel Prescott warned the residents of one of this campaign's targets after William Dawes fell off his horse and Paul Revere was captured. For the point, name this series of battles fought on April 19, 1775, which started the American Revolution.", "answer": "Battles of <b><u>Lexington and Concord</u></b> [prompt on <b><u>Lexington</u></b>; prompt on <b><u>Concord</u></b>; prompt on breakout of the <b><u>American Revolution</u></b>]  {III}", "metadata": "KG"}, {"question": "After losing the Battle of Worcester (<b>pr. WOOS-ter</b>), this man hid in an oak tree. This man's affair with Lucy Walter led to the birth of a son who lost the Battle of Sheriffmuir. Three years after his navy was attacked in the Raid on the Medway, this man signed the secret Treaty of Dover with France. This father of the Duke of Monmouth and husband of Catherine of Braganza permitted Parliament to pass the Test Act. Titus Oates concocted a fictitious plan to assassinate this man, leading to anti-Catholic hysteria. For the point, name this target of the Popish and Rye House Plots, a son of Charles I who was rose to the throne in the English Restoration.", "answer": "<b><u>Charles II</u></b> of England  {III}", "metadata": "SL"}, {"question": "This man is not Tom Evans but was accused of flirting with lobbyist and future Playboy model Paula Parkinson on a golfing trip. During a debate, this man vigorously brought up specific page references from his opponent's book, <em>Earth in the Balance</em>. This man told the Commonwealth Club of California that \"primetime TV\" mocked \"the importance of fathers.\" Lloyd Bentsen told him \"Senator, you're no Jack Kennedy\" in a debate. This man infamously misspelled the word \"potato\" while visiting an elementary school in 1992. For the point, name this Vice President of George H.W. Bush.", "answer": "James Danforth \u201cDan\u201d <b><u>Quayle</u></b>  {III}  <b>Extra Tossups </b>", "metadata": "MC"}, {"question": "In this election year, Robert MacInnes lost a seat by six votes. In this election year, Eric Gandar Dower was elected by sixty-one votes over the third place candidate, Archie Sinclair. One party's leader in this election alleged that implementing a competitor's platform would require \"some form of Gestapo.\" That competitor ran on the slogan \"Let us face the future\" and promised the creation of the National Health Service. For the point, give the year of the British general election in which the Labour Party scored a surprise victory over the Conservative Party leading to Clement Attlee replacing Winston Churchill as Prime Minister.", "answer": "<b><u>1945</u></b> United Kingdom general election  {III}", "metadata": "DW"}, {"question": "They aren't capes, but the banning of a type of this object sparked the Esquilache riots against Charles III. The barrentina is one of these objects that symbolizes Catalan independence. Two factions named for these objects were prominent during Sweden's Age of Liberty. One of these objects belonging to Tarquin the Elder was stolen and returned by an eagle. The <em>pileus</em> was a type of this object used by freed Roman slaves. During the French Revolution, cockades were used to decorate a type of this item named for Phrygia. For the point, name this clothing item exemplified by the tricorne.", "answer": "<b><u>hat</u></b>s [or <b><u>cap</u></b>s]  {III}", "metadata": "JB"}, {"question": "<em>They aren't gates, but the Chu-Han contention was briefly ended by a treaty named for one</em> <em>of these structures at Hong.</em> Examples of this structure's \"contour\" variety include the Magic one and the Flying Geese one. The legendary king Yu the Great created a system of these structures to deal with a great disaster. One of these structures was completed during the reign of Emperor Yang and begun by his father Wen of Sui. For the point, name this sort of structure, the \"grand\" one of which was used to transport grain from the Yangtze river and is the longest man-made waterway.", "answer": "<b><u>canal</u></b>s  {III}", "metadata": "JB"}, {"question": "<em>One defender of this city refused to surrender by saying, \u201cI have no reply to make...other</em> <em>than from the mouths of my cannons...\u201d</em> This city was attacked by Massachusetts Bay Colony forces under Sir William Phipps after they took Port Royal in King William\u2019s War. Sir Guy Carleton held off a siege of this city after an attack on it during which Daniel Morgan was captured, Richard Montgomery was killed, and Benedict Arnold was wounded. For the point, name this city attacked in 1775 during the American Revolution, the namesake of a French-speaking Canadian province.", "answer": "<b><u>Quebec</u></b> City [or Ville de <b><u>Quebec</u></b>]  {II}", "metadata": "PL"}, {"question": "<em>During World War II, this city was home to the Neuengamme concentration camp.</em> A World War II bombing of this city featured the first use of the \u201cWindow\u201d radar jammer, and was called Operation Gomorrah. A terrorist cell based in and named for this city played an important role in the 9/11 attacks and included Mohamed Atta among its members. By a 1937 ordinance, this city incorporated neighboring Altona, Wandsbek, and Harburg. This city was the most heavily damaged by the 1962 North Sea flood. For the point, name this German city-state on the Elbe River.", "answer": "<b><u>Hamburg</u></b>, Germany  {II}", "metadata": "SH"}], "bonuses": []}